Hello everyone, welcome back to today's another tutorial series. So today we are going to explore
the powerful minimum and the maximum function in the SQL. This allows us to find the minimum
and the maximum values in a data set okay. So first of all just explain for simply the minimum
and the maximum function. So it's function in the SQL are used to find the smallest and the
largest values respectively in the data set okay. And there are a handy tool for analyzing data.
So first of all here I can create the first example for finding the minimum value okay.
So now just let's get started and here I can create the minimum employees table okay.
So first of all here I can start this is the select then create here the minimum
and the parenthesis inside declare for the age column and here we are going to start
at statement and now first of all here I can just clear this is the minimum age from the
table's name you can use now here the employees okay. So now here define perfectly it is called
the employees table okay. So here I can use for the minimum function to find the
smallest value in the age column of the employee table okay. So first of all I can select the result
and see the output for the display okay. So just execute and you can see here first I can create okay
and then first the error so now just choose for the data set for the SQL and now
first I can again select and execute now you can see here this is the minimum
use for here 25 okay. So now just verify the employee table so you can get another
query and some step from here use the employee table okay. So now just select all and execute
you can see here the minimum 25 okay. So I hope you perfectly understand it.
So next step here we are going to find the maximum value okay. So just go for here
and first of all using for the maximum function to find the largest value in the
salary column for doing the table okay. So just change for here the age column and now here
defining the salary column and age for here the maximum. So define perfectly the maximum
salary and then just change so this is the maximum salary as the maximum salary
from the employee table okay. So now just select all and then here I can execute now.
So just execute and you can see here the maximum salary is
360,000. So you can see here the maximum salary is 60,000 okay. So in this query we can
the maximum salary of all employees as the maximum salary okay. So next step here we are going
to use the both minimum and the maximum values okay. So now just here create this function
together both the smallest and the largest values in the data set okay.
So first of all I can create just go here and now just type for select then
here I can create this minimum then the parenthesis inside we find for the age column
and use the minimum age okay and next step here we can create for this maximum for the
age column and here we can use again the maximum age okay and here select from the employee
stable okay. So this table is create the minimum and the maximum age for the employees in the
employee stable okay. So now just select all in this data query and execute now you can see here
first create for the minimum age 25 and maximum age 35 okay. So I hope you perfectly understand
so next step here you use the minimum and the maximum values over there condition okay.
So now just go here first of all here just use the code. So first create here the minimum
salary okay and as here the change the minimum salary column and here I can use for the maximum
salary okay. So this is the maximum salary and I can again change and here I can use the
salary column okay and use the maximum. So first of all here I can create the minimum salary
and the maximum salary as the maximum salary for the employee stable and next step for
just I can go the next step and then go for also another. So here I can create the where
so use the where clause for the department okay. So the department
and it is equal to create for here the IT department okay. So now just say perfectly and here
select all and let's again now here simply just select all and then execute now you can see here
print out for so first of minimum salary is 30,000 and the maximum salary is
same the combine okay. So here I can perfectly find it the condition used okay.
So I hope you perfectly learn the minimum and the maximum salary range okay. So I hope you
perfectly understand to this session and here I have completely overview the minimum and the maximum
function in the SQL okay. So I hope you perfectly understand this session. Now thank you for
Have fun watching and happy coding.